

ALINA.ROMANENKO

Ukraine, Poltava 39000 Skype: live:.cid.4f5e011b4b4d8ce2, discord: GreenMonkey#2967

Alina has six years of experience in web and blockchain development using JavaScript (React, Angular, Vue, Web3), Python (Django), Solidity, Rust, PHP(Laravel, Codelgniter, Symfony), and AWS. She has worked on a variety of projects at companies of all sizes. She has been an important problem solver in the teams and never failed to deliver quality work with his hard work and problem-solving skills. Alina really cares about user-friendliness and the performance of your application.

AVAILABILITY

Part-time

PREFERRED ENVIRONMENT

Atom, VS Code, Windows 10, MacOS

EMPLOYMENT

FRONTEND DEVELOPER, YALANTIS, L'viv, Ukraine 04/2017 – 02/2019

- Created a photo and video contest web app for a US startup, users could upload
 photos and videos and could participate in contests where the best upload would get
 prizes. The app was made with scalability in mind..
- Implemented mobile-responsive front-end pages with React, Bootstrap, and SCSS
- Contributed as part of the team that developed a new webshop app for a large retailer in Croatia.
- Made a tablet app with a custom CMS back end for the Croatian branch of Allianz, the insurance company. We migrated all the insurance sales documents to a digitalized format that they could keep up-to-date via the CMS
- Created a number of responsive web apps and pages.

Technologies: Single-page Applications (SPA), Gulp, Grunt, ECMAScript (ES6), Webpack, Responsive Design, Front-end Development, Babel, React, REST APIs, Express.is, Sass, Node.is, MySQL, PHP, CSS, HTML, JavaScript

REMOTE FULL-STACK DEVELOPER, SIGMA SOFTWARE GROUP, L'VIV, UKRAINE 06/2019 – 04/2021

- Developed Boston hospitals' medication provider search project using Django and React.
- Implemented front-end pages using React and Redux Form.
- Implemented REST APIs using Django REST framework and optimized Django ORM queries.
- Fixed mobile responsive issue on server-side rendering in Next.js using JavaScript packages such as Lodash.throttle.
- Integrated Django-packages like TinyMCE editor and customize Django admin behavior.
- Fixed Django specific issues, maintained and upgraded Django packages.
- Fixed cross-browser issues for the front-end including Chrome, IE, Firefox, and Safari..
- Redesigned the websites from scratch using create-react-app and custom Webpack configuration.
- Developed a Quora-like site using React, React Hooks front end with GraphQL for a home-care service company based in Australia.
- Developed USA's leading cloud-based workforce management, HR, and payroll software with Angular, Node.js, Express.js, GraphQL, Apollo, PostgreSQL, Bootstrap, and more.

Technologies: Django REST Framework, Django, Next.js, Mapbox, Redux Form, React, Node, Express, PHP

BLOCKCHAIN && WEB DEVELOPER, SPARKYBIT, L'VIV, UKRAINE 06/2021 – 04/2022

- Redesigned the websites from scratch using create-react-app and custom Webpack configuration.
- Developed a Quora-like site using React, React Hooks front end with GraphQL for a home-care service company based in Australia.
- Developed USA's leading cloud-based workforce management, HR, and payroll software with Angular, Node.js, Express.js, GraphQL, Apollo, PostgreSQL, Bootstrap, and more.
- Performs instructor sessions for over 150 students in Web development focused upon MongoDB, Express, React, Node.
- Manages project development cycles with the help of Trello Boards/Slack/Zoom video conferencing.
- Build Dapps with NFT mining, swap, and mining functions on Etherium, Solana and BSC chains.
- Collaborate with team members to attend metaverse creation
- Development and distribution of various smart contracts using Solidity, Rust,
 Python, and PHP

Technologies: PHP, Solidity, Rust, Python, Web3.js, AWS, Django, Node.js, Angular, React, MongoDB, MySQL

EXPERENCE

GCP Tenant App

React native app (iOS and Android) for a real estate company that rents apartments and objects, it has a number of functionalities to offer their tenants easier apartment maintenance, have access to emergency contacts, rent-paying, track updates in their neighborhood area, new apartment search, etc.

GitHub Projects

https://github.com/features/issues

Project planning for developers that allow them to create issues, break them into tasks, track relationships, add custom fields, and have conversations. Visualize large projects as spreadsheets or boards, and automate everything with code.

GrowHealthy

https://growhealthy.com/

GrowHealthy produces Florida's natural medical cannabis products to help patients improve their quality of life. I led and participated with the frontend and the backend team in building and deploying a new platform that integrates different systems and APIs.

OTHER

Software Development, Blockchain Development, AWS, Backend, APIs, Authentication, Technology, Technical Leadership, SOAP, Minimum Viable Product (MVP), Mobile Architecture, Middleware, Software as a Service (SaaS), CTO, Fintech, Mobile Apps, Mobile APIs, Containerization, Containers, Software Architecture, Writing & Editing, Stripe Payments, Planning, Back-end Development, Firebase Cloud Functions, Data Scraping, Payment APIs, SOLID Principles, Open Source, Communication, Leadership, Architecture, Web Scraping, RESTful APIs, Mentorship & Coaching, Native Mobile Apps, Web Development, Fullstack, Team Management, Distributed Team Management, Technical Hiring, Interviews, Interviewing, Code Review, Source Code Review, Push Notifications, Scripting, SaaS, API Integration, Integration Testing, System Integration Testing (SIT), OAuth, CI/CD Pipelines, System Architecture, Progressive Web Applications (PWA), Cloud Services, Consul, Financial Services, WebSockets, FindBugs, Google Cloud Functions, Cloud, Serverless, Protocol Buffers, Algorithms, Data Structures, Analytics, User Experience (UX), Concurrency, Trading, Mathematics, Software, Cordova, Kotlin/Native, Mobile Banking, Machine Learning, Big Data, Offshore Team Management, Online Banking, Team Leadership, Google, Presentations, Tech Sales, Public Speaking, Technical Writing, fiserv

EDUCATION

2013-2017

BACHELOR OF COMPUTER SCIENCE,

TARAS SHEVCHENKO NATION UNIVERSITY, KIEV

SKILLS

LANGUAGES

Python, HTML, CSS4, CSS, JavaScript, Python 3, ECMAScript (ES6), TypeScript, GraphQL, HTML5, Java, SCSS, Solidity, Rust, Web3.js

FRAMEWORKS

Cypress.io, Django REST Framework, Flask, Redux, Django, Angular, Express.js, MUI (Material UI), Vuetify, FeathersJS, Bootstrap, Next.js, React Native, Boost, NestJS

LIBRARIES/APIS

Antd, REST APIs, Flask-RESTful, React, Node.js, Redux-Saga, ApexCharts.js, Vue, Highcharts, AmplifyJS, Vue 2, Redux Form, Reselect, RxJS, Three.js

TOOLS

MongoDB Atlas, Mongoose, Redux Thunk, Webpack, VS Code, XAMPP, POSTMAN

PLATFORMS

Android, Amazon Web Services (AWS), Firebase, Amazon EC2, Twilio, Google Cloud Platform (GCP), Docker, AWS Lambda, Blockchain, MacOS, Mapbox, Ethereum

STORAGE

NoSQL, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Cloud Firestore, MongoDB, Elasticsearch

• OTHER

TypeORM, Hooks, AWS, Ajax, Material Design, Firebase Cloud Functions, Frontend, Blockchain Development, Apollo, Semantic UI, Microsoft Azure, Linux Administration, Progressive Web Applications (PWA), Windows 10

PARADIGMS

DevOps: Git, Github, Heroku, Digital Ocean